[Music]
alright thanks for joining pictured
metal detecting tonight fresh off the
truck today I just got a shipment in
from my good friends and partners at
Kelly CO detector that some folks have
out there it's just starting to get up
through the distributors I know I've
been waiting for it very anxious for it
to right that's the note to macro
simplex plus a lot of hype about this
machine out there right now a lot of
people looking for it for what it brings
to the table and and for the price point
that it's coming out at as we looked at
it look at it here like it says it's the
first waterproof detector on the market
that offers the high-end features that
this detector has at an entry level
price this is the wireless headphone
version and it runs about three hundred
thirty nine dollars retail there's also
a non wireless version which you can
connect your own wired headphones to
it's about two hundred and fifty four
dollars an incredible price point for
some of the things this detector can do
for instance it's got a built in
rechargeable battery the iron volume
knobs discrimination frequency shift
it's got a vibration capability for
those hearing-impaired or in a situation
where they don't want the beats and
squeaks you get just vibration it's got
the backlight keypad LCD and an LED
flashlight feature where I actually
shines down on the ground so if you're
night hunting land beach so on and so
forth it's got a built-in flashlight
very helpful it's got a double D 11 H
double D search coil and like some of
the other more modern detectors out on
the market right now
it's a online firmware update capability
so you can keep your software updated
keep the capabilities up to speed on
this on this detector we look at the end
here
there's the eliminates double D search
coil you're some of your connectors your
headphone adapter
wired headphones which this wireless
version does come with as well
so you can go wireless or otherwise
charging cable charging adapter the
headphones and another big feature of
this machine other than the waterproof
bit of it and the actual technical
specifications you know what it can do
is the fact that it is waterproof down
to ten feet deep so it's you know land
or water detector and the telescoping
shaft on this we'll take a look at that
in just a minute it telescopes down to
as small as 25 inches either for
transport so you can put it right in the
back of your car back to your truck
telescope down or down to that 25 inches
for underwater you so you can dive with
it can go down to 10-foot and use it
underwater so pretty versatile and
versatile you know it's got field mode
so you're out detecting in your field
looking for relics or if you're at the
park either right yourself maybe you're
there with your family with your kids
and I take the detector with you
telescope down and carry nice and small
hit hit the park and go off the
technique do it while you're there or if
you're on vacation at the beach again
you can have it down there hit the surf
or up on the sand either way so pretty
versatile so let's take a look inside
the box and see what we've got
so there we go there's what what you see
when you open the box first thing you
see is a note to macro simplex plus hat
nice black hat pretty sharp and then
we've got a little card here says metal
detecting code of ethics it says do not
enter private property without the
owner's permission refill all holes
remove and dispose of all trash found
respect natural life and natural life
and protect the environment good rules
to live by
I've actually got these on the back of
my business card that I use when I go to
seek permissions detecting permissions
so I can flip it over and say this is
what I'm all about good rules to follow
it's got the owner's manual and warranty
2.4 gigahertz wireless headphones manual
and there's the 2.4 gigahertz wireless
headphones right there we've got a bag
of items here so we've got the velcro
webbing strap that goes up around the
arm cuff so that you can detect long
duration with your arms strapped in you
know and that's actually another item
I'm on jump back out quick it says on
the front this entire detectors 2.9
pounds
so not the heaviest detector out there
not maybe not quite totally the lightest
but that's a pretty light detectors a
2.9 pounds you'll be able to swing this
thing all day long without much problem
at all we've got the charging core and
we'll just take a look at this green end
here that's the connector end that
connects into the back of the control
head so you screw that in and then this
end connects to the charging adapter
which goes into the wall so you got a
good firm connection and they went with
the with the screw in very firm
connection so no doubt that that's going
to stay put
it's got an adapter here that also goes
in that same port if you want to use
your wired headphones it's got a quarter
inch jack so any of the standard metal
detector headphones out there can be
used on that
and then of course the screw bolt and
screw for the hold coil onto the bottom
of the shaft so we'll go straight into
the box and there's what you see in the
box itself as far as the detector itself
so we'll pull that out here and there's
the main business part of the detector
with the control head screen arm cuff
and the rubberized handle one of the
another one of the things I was looking
forward to very firm grip on that thing
that should make detecting in wet
conditions or underwater a whole lot
easier you're not going to lose that
grip and then it's got your two
connections on the back for the coil
goes in and where your headphones
connect to or the charging cable
connects to right there and then right
here we've got part of the shaft the
middle part of the shaft with one of the
levers on there for the telescoping
portion of the shaft
slip that off to the side and in the
bottom of the box
you've got your bottom part of the shaft
where the coil goes and there's the 11
inch double D coil okay so we'll set
that aside for just a second and just
taking a look at this I thought I'd put
this together real quick just to show
you how simple this really is with the
telescoping capability so this is your
bottom part of the shaft where the coil
goes you just take that connects right
in there boom take that right into the
top part of there and you're in business
when you want to telescope it down it
slides all the way up in connected and
it's that small and once it coils on the
end there that's pretty small for easy
to travel with or detect underwater with
with that rub rubber grip so that's
going to be very helpful so we're gonna
put all this together tonight we're
going to calibrate it and we're going to
be cold and soil tomorrow outside of
Richmond Virginia and we're gonna see
what the simpler macro simplex
north-america simplex can do and we'll
have this video out on our Patriot metal
detecting YouTube channel and on Patriot
metal detecting comm if you want to take
a look back at it and check it out again
and we'll also have more videos
not to show you what what this thing can
do all right yeah we will talk to you
later